

+38269372968

alperenkoksel@yandex.com

Podgorica, Montenegro

in alperenk

github.com/AlperennK

QA Engineer

# education

Telecommunication Engineering, Bachelor's Degree Istanbul Technical University 2006 - 2011

### key skills

Python, Pytest, Java, Junit, Load Testing, API Testing, Docker, Selenium, SQL, Cucumber, Jira, Jenkins, Test Automation, Process Automation, Test Planning

#### certifications

ISTQB Foundation Level / 2017 Cert No: 51 CTLL:2203

Applied Data Science with Python University of Michigan (Online Specialization)

#### about me

Knowledgeable, resourceful and efficiency-oriented innovator with expertise in web services, application development focused on test automation with strong understanding of Agile and CI/CD concepts and experience in Python, Pytest, Locust, Kafka, Selenium, Java, Junit, RestAssured, ActiveMQ, Jenkins, API testing.

professional experience

# Test Automation Engineer Libertex Group / Montenegro / June 2018 - Present

Creation of automation framework from scratch using Java, Junit, Allure. Developing auto test suites in order to test producer apps both for ActiveMQ and Kafka.

- Created test automation with Python for WebServices and plugins
- Created test automation with RestAssured for RestAPIs from scratch.
- Implemented fully functional API wrapper for Metatrader5 Web API.
- Implemented load testing with Locust.io

# Test Automation Engineer Turk Telekom / Istanbul. Turkey / 2013 - 2018

Maintenance of existing automation test framework for IPTV product Tivibu.. Generated user acceptance tests based on product requirement specification..

- Creation of test automation framework for UI with Java, Selenium.
- Created acceptance test scenarios for Web and Mobile endpoints of IPTV service.
- Perform load tests for STBs with RedRat.



**QA ENGINEER** 

### professional skills

Python, Pytest, Docker, Selenium, SQL, Cucumber, Jira, Jenkins, Test Automation, Process Automation, Test Planning

### experience (continued)

#### **DESIGN VERIFICATION TESTER**

Airties Wireless Networks / Istanbul, Turkey/ 2012- 2013

Creation and maintenance of regression, smoke, end-to-end and exploratory testing. Obtained necessary testing steps and cases based on product requirement specifications for various STB, gateway, access point devices.

- Achieved test suite generation for protocols such as DLNA, IGMP.
- Implemented testing setup for automation, automated functional testing and load testing scenarios.

#### interests

Snowboarding, Motorcycles, Travelling, Cycling, Modern Art, Swimming

## professional development

HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers (Ongoing )

Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization (Ongoing) University of California, San Diego (Online, Coursera)

### professional references

Yuriy Plyaskin Manager Forex Club +79169369203

Skype: plyaskin.yuri